<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./dendrogram.png" type="Visualizer"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Hierarchical Cluster Assigner (JavaScript)</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Creates an interactive JavaScript which displays the results of hierarchical clustering and enables cluster assignment.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node takes a hierarchical cluster tree and the
				<b>same input table</b>
				that has been used for the creating
				the clustering, and creates an
				interactive dendrogram using JavaScript. The interactive view allows
				for the selection of a threshold, which is used to define clusters
				and assign rows to clusters.
			</p>
			<p>
				This node is only intended for small data tables (&lt;65,500
				rows).
			</p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Cluster assignment column name">
				Sets the name of the assigned cluster column in
				the output data table.
			</option>
			<option name="Assign clusters based on">
				Select if you want to assign clusters based on a
				fixed number or based on a
				distance threshold.
			</option>
			<option name="Number of clusters">
				The number of clusters (i.e. the level in the
				cluster tree) that should
				be created.
			</option>
			<option name="Distance threshold">
				The distance below which clusters should be
				selected.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="View Configuration">
			<option name="Show warnings in view">
				If checked, warning messages will be displayed in
				the view when they
				occur.
			</option>
			<option name="Create image at outport">
				If checked an SVG image will be created at the
				outport.
			</option>
			<option name="Width of image (in px)">
				The width in pixels of the generated SVG image.
			</option>
			<option name="Height of image (in px)">
				The height in pixels of the generated SVG image.
			</option>
			<option name="Chart title" optional="true">
				The title shown above the
				image. If left blank, no title will be shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Chart subtitle" optional="true">
				The subtitle shown
				above the image. If left blank, no subtitle will be
				shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable cluster labels">
				Displays cluster labels in the view, and enables
				editing of these labels.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable cluster colors">
				If enabled, tree leaves will be
				assigned colors
				based on their cluster membership. Otherwise, the leaf colors will
				be determined by those
				specified in the input data table.
			</option>
			<option name="Resize view to fill window">
				Checking this option resizes the view so that it
				fills the window.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable view edit controls">
				If checked, all edit controls selected below will
				be rendered in the
				view. Unchecking this option disables all edit
				controls.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable title and subtitle editing">
				Displays a text box to change title or subtitle.
			</option>
			<option name="Display full screen button">
				Displays a button enabling full screen mode.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable number of clusters specification">
				Allows for cluster assignment via number of
				clusters from the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable numeric specification of threshold">
				Allows the threshold to be set to a specified
				numeric value from within the view. Regardless if this is
				enabled/disabled, the threshold can always manually be set with the
				horizontal bar in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable scale options">
				Enables modification of the y-axis scale (i.e.
				linear, logarithmic, etc.) within the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable selection">
				When this option is checked, data points can be
				selected in the view. The selection appears in an
				appended column of
				the data table.
			</option>
			<option name="Selection column name">
				Sets the name of the selection column in the
				output data table.
			</option>
			<option name="Publish selection events">
				Checking this option ensures that other views are
				notified whenever the
				selection in the current view is changed.
			</option>
			<option name="Subscribe to selection events">
				Checking this option ensures that this view is
				notified whenever other views publish new selections.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable panning">
				Enable panning on the view. To start panning click and drag the mouse.
				Note if panning and drag zooming are enabled,
				panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl key and dragging the mouse.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable mouse wheel zooming">
				Enable zooming on the view using the mouse wheel.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable drag zooming">
				Enable zooming on the view by dragging the mouse and drawing a zoom
				rectangle. Dragging from the top-left down
				will create a zoom rectangle, dragging from the bottom right up will
				reset the zoom to fit the extends of the plot. Note if panning and
				drag zooming are enabled, panning can be achieved by holding the Ctrl
				key and dragging the mouse.
			</option>
			<option name="Show zoom reset button">
				Renders a button to resize the plot to its extent.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Dendrogram">
		<p>Displays the resulting dendrogram with a bar for selecting the
			threshold value, which changes the cluster assignments.
		</p>
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Cluster Tree" index="0">
			The hierarchical cluster tree
			that has been created by the hierarchical clustering node.
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Data to Cluster" index="1">
			The
			<b>same data table</b>
			that has been used to create the clusters.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Image Port" index="0">
			An SVG representation of this
			view.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Clustered Data" index="1">
			The input data table with
			an appended
			column denoting cluster assignment.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>