<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" 
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd"
	icon="./document_viewer.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Tagged Document Viewer (JavaScript)</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Visualizes documents.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
		  <p>
			This node visualizes terms and tags of a document using
			<a href="http://brat.nlplab.org/embed.html">the Brat JS library</a>. 
			Each term will be highlighted and its corresponding tags will be
			displayed above it. The highlighting colors are static depending on
			the tags.
		  </p>
		  <p>
            The node supports custom CSS styling. You can simply put CSS rules
            into a single string and set it as a flow variable 'customCSS' in
            the node configuration dialog. You will find the list of available
            classes and their description on our
            <a href="https://knime.com/css-styling">documentation page</a>.
            </p>
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">
			<description>
			General view and display options
			</description>
			<option name="Document Column">
				The column containing the documents to show.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable pagination">
				Enable or disable the pagination feature globally. When disabled the table is rendered whole on one
                page. When enabled use the options below to further refine the pagination settings.
			</option>
			<option name="Initial page size">
				Set the page size to be used on initial layout. A page size is defined as the number of documents the view
                displays on one page. If the page size change control is enabled the page length can be changed in the
                view.
			</option>
			<option name="Enable page size change control">
				Enable or disable the control to change the page size interactively in the view.
			</option>
			<option name="Selectable page sizes">
				Define a comma-separated list of allowed page sizes for the page size control.
			</option>
			<option name="No. of rows to display">
				Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for this visualization.
			</option>
			<option name="Title" optional="true">
				An optional title to be displayed above the tiles. Leave blank if no title is desired.
			</option>
			<option name="Subtitle" optional="true">
				 An optional subtitle to be displayed above the tiles. Leave blank if no subtitle is desired.
			</option>
			<option name="Show line numbers">
				If checked line numbers are shown next to the document.
			</option>
			<option name="Display document tags">
				If checked document tags are shown in the document.
			</option>
			<option name="Show title in document">
				If checked the title of each document is additionally rendered into each document.
				This is useful, if the title itself has tags.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Interactivity">
			<description>
				The JavaScript Tagged Document Viewer allows for several ways of interactivity. Please use the options below to
                configure which features will be activated on the view and further configuration of interactive
                properties.
			</description>
			<option name="Enable selection">
                If checked a checkbox is rendered in the top left corner of each document. The selection, when applied,
                will be represented in the output table as a new boolean column.
            </option>
            <option name="Subscribe to filter events">
                If checked, the view reacts when applied filters have been changed.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable 'Clear Selection' button">
                If checked a button is displayed above the documents, to clear any selection that is applied, regardless of
                current search and/or filter settings.
            </option>
            <option name="Show selected documents only">
                If checked, only documents which are selected are displayed.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable 'Show selected documents only' option">
                If checked, a checkbox to switch on and off the mode of displaying only selected documents is rendered in 
                the view.
            </option>
            <option name="Publish selection events">
                If checked, notifies other interactive views when user changes the selection in the current view. See
                also "Subscribe to selection events".
            </option>
            <option name="Subscribe to selection events">
                If checked, the view reacts on notifications from other interactive views that the selection has been
                changed. See also "Publish selection events".
            </option>
            <option name="Selection column name">
                The name of the boolean column containing the selection.
            </option>
		</tab>
			
	</fullDescription>
	<interactiveView name="Tagged Document View">
		Displays the visualization of the
		tagged documents.
	</interactiveView>
	<ports>
		<inPort name="Tagged documents input table" index="0">
			The input table containing the tagged documents.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Input data and view selection" index="0">
			Data table containing the input data appended with a column, that
			represents the selection made in the document viewer.
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>