<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./optics.png" type="Learner" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>OPTICS Cluster Compute</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
      OPTICS (Ordering Points To Identify the Clustering Structure) is a distance-based clustering algorithm. This node computes reachability distance table, based on which clustering is then performed.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
	    <intro>
		    <p>The implementation of the OPTICS algorithm in KNIME consists of two nodes: the OPTICS Cluster Compute node and the OPTICS Cluster Assigner node.  Here you will find a brief description of the algorithm, followed by a description of the OPTICS Cluster Compute node.</p>
		<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OPTICS_algorithm">OPTICS</a> is an algorithm for finding clusters in spatial data.  It was
first described in <a href="http://www.dbs.ifi.lmu.de/Publikationen/Papers/OPTICS.pdf">Mihael Ankerst, Markus M. Breunig, Hans-Peter Kriegel, Jörg Sander (1999). "OPTICS: Ordering Points To Identify the Clustering Structure". 
        ACM SIGMOD international conference on Management of data. ACM Press. pp. 49–60</a> and is based on DBSCAN.  Like DBSCAN,
it is a <i>density-based</i> clustering algorithm, that is, it groups data points that are densely packed together in some
contiguous region of the data space into
clusters.  Unlike DBSCAN, it can detect
clusters of varying density.</p>

<p>The basic idea shared by DBSCAN and OPTICS is that a data point <i>p</i>
belongs to a cluster if it has sufficiently many sufficiently close
neighbors. "Sufficiently close" is modeled with a parameter <b>epsilon</b> (the
neighborhood radius of <i>p</i>), "sufficiently many" with a parameter <b>Minimum
	Points</b> (the minimum number of points that must be within <b>epsilon</b> of <i>p</i> in
order for <i>p</i> to belong to the core of a cluster.)</p>

<p>DBSCAN first checks the epsilon-neighborhood of each point in the data
	set.  If there are more than <b>Minimum Points</b> points in the
	epsilon-neighborhood of a point <i>p</i>, these points form a cluster. DBSCAN
then checks the epsilon-neighborhoods of these points to see if they in
turn contain more than <b>Minimum Points</b> data points. If they do, these
data points also become part of the cluster.  DBSCAN continues in this
way until no new point can be added to the cluster.</p>

<p>While this algorithm will find all the clusters with the density
determined by the the chosen values for <b>epsilon</b> and <b>Minimum Points</b>, it
may miss higher-density clusters that are contained in these
clusters. These higher-density clusters become visible only at some
<b>epsilon-prime</b> &lt;e epsilon. The problem is that there is no way of knowing these
<b>epsilon-prime</b> values in advance, so all one can do is run DBSCAN for as many
<b>epsilon-prime</b> values as feasible.</p>

<p>OPTICS solves this problem by ordering the points in the data set and by
associating with each point two values: its core-distance and its
reachability distance (for definitions, see the link above). This
information is enough to find all density-based clusters in the data set
for any <b>epsilon-prime</b> &lt;e <b>epsilon</b> (for details on the algorithm, see the link
above).</p>

<p>Since both core-distance and reachability-distance are ultimately
defined in terms of <b>epsilon</b> and <b>Minimum Points</b>, the only inputs needed
to run OPTICS are values for these parameters.</p>
        </intro>
                
        <option name="Distance Selection">Optional. When the distance port is not connected, select the distance metric to be used.</option>
        <option name="Select Column" >Optional. When the distance port is not connected, select the columns for which distance is to be calculated.  Columns can be selected manually or by means of regular expressions.  Columns listed in the left (red) pane will be excluded, columns in the right (green) pane will be included.  Use the buttons in the center to move columns from one pane to the other.</option>
	<option name="Minimum points">The minimum number of points within <b>epsilon</b> of a point <i>p</i> in order for <i>p</i> to belong to the core of a cluster.</option>
	<option name="Epsilon">The neighborhood radius of a point <i>p</i>.  Points within this distance of each other are considered neighbors.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data Port">The input data.</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Distance Model Port">Optional. The configured distance model from one of the Distances nodes.</inPort>    
        <outPort index="0" name="Model Port">The calculated model to be used in OPTICS Cluster Assigner.</outPort>
    </ports> 
</knimeNode>
